译者:微博@Emtee
母亲的双眼
圣弗朗西斯在树林中独自生活了很多年
Saint Francis spent many years living alone in the woods.
有一天晚上 他看到一位天使在天空中燃烧着
Then one night, he saw an angel burning in sky.
他醒来时...
And when he woke up...
有了圣痕
he had stigmata.
但孤独会对心智做奇怪的事
But loneliness can do strange things to the mind.
最终 他死于一种也会
Eventually he died of an eye condition
导致精神病的眼疾
that also would have caused psychosis.
当心
弗朗西斯卡
Francisca.
你干什么了
母亲
我们能过去看看它们吗
母牛眼非常类似人眼
Cow eyes are very similar to human eyes.
结构几乎完全一样
The construction is almost exactly the same.
唯一的区别是它们更大
The only difference is they're bigger.
在葡萄牙时 我们常用母牛练习外科手术
In Portugal, we used to practice surgery on cows.
而这里 他们用人来练习
Here, they practice on people.
他们是这样杀死它的
This is how they kill it.
我们所看到的一切...
都经由此物
- 弗朗西斯卡 - 弗朗西斯卡?
- Francisca. - Francisca?
我刚想认识下你女儿呢 我叫查理
I was just getting to know your daughter. I'm Charlie.
你的丈夫在家吗
Is your husband at home?
他随时会回来
He'll be home any second now.
但不管你想卖什么 我们都没兴趣
But we're not interested in whatever you're trying to sell.
我没想卖什么给你们
I'm not trying to sell you anything.
我能进去一会儿吗
May I come inside for a second?
就用下洗手间 一会会儿
Just to use the restroom. It'll only take a second.
你家很漂亮 你在这里住了很久吗
You have a lovely home. Have you lived here a long time?
走过客厅 右边就是卫生间
The bathroom is through the living room to the right.
谢谢
Thanks.
你的丈夫通常都迟归吗
Is your husband usually late?
你说你估计他随时会到
You said you expected him here any second.
走过客厅 你右边就是卫生间
Bathroom is through the living room, to your right.
你能带我去吗
Would you show me?
我觉得你该给我带路
I think you should show me the way.
夫人
Ma'am.
我在尽量有礼貌
I'm trying to be polite.
在我开始变得不讲理之前 我们可以再试一次
Now, we can try this one more time before I start to become unreasonable.
我很抱歉 先生 但我真的要你离开了
I am sorry, sir, but I really need you to leave.
我真不知道你要干嘛
I don't quite know what you're planning.
嘿 弗朗妮
Hey there, Franny.
我要你坐在那边的椅子上 保持安静
I'm gonna need you to sit over there on that chair and be real quiet.
你能做到吗
Can you do that for me?
现在 你不如做个好主人
Now, why don't you be a good host
带我去卫生间吧
and show me where that bathroom is?
很好
Well, all right now.
进步很大
Onwards and upwards.
今天报道自州消防局长办公室的消息称
Reporting from the State Fire Marshal's Office today,
所有市政当局都被要求对一种已被发现是
request for all municipal authorities to ban the sale of an imported ragdoll,
高度易燃的进口布娃娃 封禁销售
which has been found to be highly flammable.
州消防局长乔治·查诺维克说 已将此事告知
State Fire Marshal George Chanovec says every fire department in the state
州内的每个消防部门 这种娃娃身长15英寸...
has been contacted about it. The doll stands 15 inches high...
体内充塞了稻草 脚下有名字印花 A.E.萨顿
The bodies are stuffed with straw, and the name A.E. Sutton stamped on the foot.
消防局长说 这种娃娃售价不到一美元 通常来说...
Fire Marshal says the dolls, which sold for less than a dollar and for usually...
你母亲呢
Where's your mother?
我不可能离开她的
I couldn't leave her.
你为什么在日历上标记这个日期
Why'd you mark the calendar towards this date?
听着 我希望这事发生 可并不想看到它发生
Look, I want this to happen. I don't want to see it happen.
几分钟后就结束了
It'll be over in a few minutes.
我有事要做
I've got things to do.
在这里看不到绞刑
Can't see the hanging from here.
只能听到
Just hear it.
听到?
Hear it?
没错 绞刑听上去和看上去一样惨
Yeah, hanging sounds almost as bad as it looks.
活门砰地一开
Trap door bangs open.
你想吃点什么吗
Do you want something to eat?
几个看的家伙很可能会...
Probably a few fellows watching will give a...
- 爸爸 -...欢呼叫嚷
- Daddy? - ...whoop or a holler.
怎么了
Trouble?
他们跟我说 我去得太晚了
I got there too late, they told me.
你母亲的事 我需要帮忙
I need help with your mother.
- 有什么问题吗  - 弗朗妮?
- Something wrong? - Franny?
没 只是...
No, it's...
- 我从没见过人这么少的镇子  - 弗朗妮
- just that I've never seen a lonesomer town. - Franny?
好吧 这只是因为...
Well, it's just that...
- 所有人都不敢看着卡特莱特父子死去 - 弗朗妮
- everyone's afraid to watch the Cartwrights die. - Franny!
并不是所有人 那边的日历表明 有人一直在算着日子
Not everyone. That calendar there says someone's been counting the days.
弗朗妮
Franny!
你还得管好这个问题
You will have to take care of this.
弗朗妮
Franny!
我和小乔发现杜斯·马丁死了
Me and little Joe found Deuce Martin dead.
- 弗朗妮  - 死了?
- Franny! - Dead?
弗朗妮 弗朗 弗朗
Franny! Fran, Fran!
弗朗妮 弗朗妮 弗朗妮 弗朗妮
Franny! Franny! Franny! Franny!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你需要缝针
You needed stitches.
你笑什么
Why are you laughing?
为什么是我们
Why us?
你们让我进去的
You let me in.
你以前就这么干过
You've done this before.
你为什么这么做
Why do you do it?
这感觉很棒
It feels amazing.
你会杀了我 对吗
You're gonna kill me, right?
我为什么要杀了你
Why would I kill you?
你是我唯一的朋友
You're my only friend.
我要管好你
I'm gonna take care of you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
从俄亥俄来的一路上都吃的这种食物?
Been eating this kind of food all the way from Ohio?
是的 先生
We have, sir.
好吧 你再一直分给他 你就没得剩了
Well, you keep shoveling it out to him, you're not gonna have any left.
你们要去哪
Where are you headed?
我们想在这周结束前到斯莱特斯维尔
We hope to be in Slatersville by week's end.
听说那里有个又大又富饶的山谷
Heard word of a large fertile valley there.
如果可以 我们想买块地安定下来
And God willing, we hope to buy land and settle in peace.
- 他不会再吵了 - ...很贵啊
- He won't make any more noise.  - ...pretty expensive.
是啊 我们工作了很多年 把所有钱都存一起了
Yes, and we work for many years put all of our money together.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Daddy.
开始一段全新的生活是我们的梦想
It is our dream to start a fresh new life.
爸爸
求你了 爸爸
父亲
你好
Hello.
我知道你在这里 妈妈
我能感觉到你在我身边
审讯时 我跟你说了我看到了什么
I told you what I saw at the trial.
-  萨莉 你撒谎了  -  小乔 没必要这样
- Sally, you lied. - Little Joe, no need for that.
你弄疼这位女士了
You were hurting the lady.
我不是故意要弄疼你 萨莉 我很抱歉
I didn't mean to hurt you, Sally, I'm sorry.
我只是想要你说出真相 仅此而已
I just wanted you to tell the truth, that's all.
我们在这边于事无补 去看看巴尼·奥格登吧
We're not doing any good here. Let's go see Barney Ogden.
再见 夫人
Ma'am.
我想你 爸爸
现在我不得不独自一人了 爸爸
我好想你
我不想你离开
为什么 爸爸
你丢下我独自一人...
为什么 爸爸 为什么
醒醒啊
唐娜酒吧 营业中
你住附近?
So, you live close by?
要过几个镇
A few towns over.
你房子好整洁
Your house is so neat.
谢谢
Thank you.
要喝什么吗
Can I get you anything?
不用
I'm okay.
你在这里住了很久吗
Have you lived here a long time?
一辈子了
My whole life.
这曾是你父母家吗
Was this your parents' house?
是的
Yes.
你现在一个人住在这吗
Do you live here alone now?
抱歉 我问的问题太多了
I'm sorry, I'm asking so many questions.
我紧张时就会问很多问题
I ask a lot of questions when I'm nervous.
为什么紧张
Why are you nervous?
我不是经常这样
I don't do this very often.
怎样
Do what?
和别人回家
Go home with people.
我也是
Neither do I.
好吧 我们俩都有尴尬的理由了
Okay, so we both have an excuse to be awkward.
这是你的母亲吗
Is this your mother?
是的
Yes.
她很漂亮
She's beautiful.
过去的事了
She was.
她是个什么样的人
What was she like?
她是个很好的母亲
She was a wonderful mother.
还有呢
What else?
我不知道
I don't know.
说嘛 随便说
Come on. Anything.
她是做什么的
What did she do?
她在葡萄牙时是一名外科医生
She was a surgeon in Portugal.
哪种
What kind?
眼科
Eyes.
我小时候
When I was little,
我们一起做外科切割
we used to do the sections together.
我记得我着迷于
I remember I was fascinated
身体内部的样子
by how the inside of the body looked.
她总希望有朝一日我能成为一名外科医生
She always hoped I would be a surgeon one day.
我以前在学校解剖过一只猫
I dissected a cat once in school.
那种东西总让我作呕
That sort of stuff always grossed me out.
她出了什么事
What happened to her?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不该问的
I shouldn't have asked.
有人杀了她
Someone killed her.
什么
What?
那你爸爸呢
What about your dad?
我杀了他
I killed him.
不是吧
No, really.
真的
Really.
什么
What?
你不是认真的吧
You're not serious, are you?
我认真的
Yeah.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没怎么
Nothing.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这很没趣
That wasn't funny.
非常抱歉
So sorry.
不用 我...没关系的 我...
No, I'm... it's okay. I...
我想我也许该快点回家了
I should probably think about heading home soon.
为什么 请别走
Why? Please don't go.
- 我可以打电话给我妈妈 - 不用 不用 我开车送你回家
- I can just call my mom. - No. No. I'll drive you home.
不了 没事的
No, it's okay.
我开车送你回家 请别走 请别走
I'll drive you home. Please don't go. Please don't go.
不用...没事的
No, no, it's... it's okay.
- 别走 - 我...听着 我只是有点累了
- No. - I... listen, I'm just kind of tired.
- 我要走了 - 别走
- I'm just gonna go. - Please.
- 我...要走了...  - 别走
- I'm... I'm just gonna... - Don't go.
- 我要走了 好吗  - 求你了 别走
- I'm gonna go, okay? - Please, stop.
我只是有点累了 好吗
I'm just a little tired, okay?
你说得没错...
这感觉...
...很棒
现在他会永远在你身边
妈妈 照顾好爸爸
我该怎么办
我不能再独自一人了
母亲 请帮帮我
我该怎么办
家庭
没事的 小家伙
It's okay, little guy.
他只是...他有点挑
He's just... he's a little fussy.
没事的
It's okay.
你能把那东西放回他嘴里吗
Would you mind putting that back in his mouth?
谢谢
Thank you.
宝贝
Baby.
别哭啦
Don't cry.
就顺着这条路 对吗
So, you're just up this way, right?
没错
Yes.
好的
Okay.
过个愉快的下午 好吗
Have a wonderful afternoon, okay?
我能抱下安东尼奥吗
You think I could just hold Antonio?
抱歉 我们...我们真的得走了
I'm sorry. We... we really have to get going.
求你了 我能就抱他一会儿吗
Please, can I hold him just for a little bit?
- 好吗 - 好吧 好吧 快点就行
- Okay? - Okay, okay, just do it quick.
就一会儿 当然可以
A quick one. Yes, of course. Of course we can.
- 嘿 宝贝 - 来吧 小家伙
- Hey, baby. - Come on, little guy.
没错 今天我们交了一个新朋友 她要抱抱你
Yeah, we made a new friend today. Look at that. She's just gonna hold you.
没事的 没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
好了 让他抬着头
Okay, so you just wanna hold his head up.
- 嗨 宝贝 你好 宝贝 - 做得不错 他喜欢他的小...
- Hi, baby. Hello, baby. - Good job. He likes his little...
他的小...
His little...
谢谢你 母亲
这是你能给我的最好的礼物
你在...说什么
What are you... saying?
你在干什么 不要
What are you doing? No.
别走 站住 别伤害他 求你了
No! Stop! Don't hurt him, please!
别伤害我的孩子 请别伤害他
Don't hurt my baby! Stop! Please don't hurt him!
请别伤害他 求你了
Please don't hurt him, please!
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
- 别叫咯 - 请别这样
- Don't scream. - Please don't do this.
- 请把他还给我 - 宝贝
- Please give him back to me. - Baby.
请远离他
Please get away from him.
我不会让你出事的
洛伦先生...
Mr. Loren...
我劝你现在取消这个宴会
I advise you to call this party off now.
鬼魂已经在移动了 这不是个好兆头
The ghosts are already moving and that's a bad sign.
我代我的妻子表示歉意 她要晚点来
Let me apologize for my wife, she'll join us later.
- 要喝什么  - 加冰威士忌
- What do we have? - Scotch with ice.
- 博士呢 - 一样
- Doctor? - I'll have the same.
好了 在宴会开始前 我们来过下细节
Now, before the party begins, let's go over the details.
看门人会在午夜离开时 把我们锁在里面
The caretakers will leave at midnight locking us in here
一直到他们早上回来
until they come back in the morning.
门一旦锁上 就没办法出去了
Once the door is locked, there's no way out.
窗户有着监狱引以为傲的栏杆
The windows have bars that a jail would be proud of.
安东尼奥
Antonio?
吃晚餐了
没电力 没电话
There's no electricity, no phone.
数英里内都没人
No one within miles.
所以 没办法呼救
So, no way to call for help.
妈妈
你醒着吗
这只是梦 这只是梦 这只是梦 这只是梦
It's only a dream. It's only a dream. It's only a dream. It's only a dream.
妈妈 那是谁
什么
What?
里面有个人
你是不是进过谷仓了
Did you go in the barn?
那是谁
我跟你说了 永远别进谷仓
I told you to never go in the barn.
告诉我该做什么 母亲
请告诉我该做什么
我做的一切都是为了你
我只想要我们在一起
我会不惜一切和你在一起
泰然自若地对待喧杂与匆忙...
...并记住 无声之中是多么安宁
不管你是否明白...
宇宙都按着自身规律而演变
母亲...
我好想你
我想让你骄傲
我希望你能见见安东尼奥
他很完美
我只想要我们都再次相聚
宝贝 宝贝 醒醒 宝贝
Baby! Baby, wake up. Baby.
- 怎么了 - 你知道我有多爱你 对吗
- What's wrong? - You know how much I love you, right?
- 怎么了 - 没事 没事
- What's wrong? - Nothing's wrong, nothing's wrong.
无论你知道了什么 都别改变你对我的感情 好吗
Whatever you learn, don't let it change how you feel about me, okay?
- 谁来了 - 开门 开门 是警察
- Who's here? - Open up. Open up, it's the police.
警察
Police!
来 来 宝贝 快 快点
Come on, come on, baby. Come on. You're fast.
- 快 快来 - 已清查 去楼上
- Come on. Come on. - Clear! Upstairs.
- 楼上 - 二楼 上
- Upstairs. - Second floor. Let's go.
你们不能带走我的孩子...
- 举起手来 - 放下武器
- Up in the air! - Drop the weapon!
举起手来
Hands up!
妈妈
Mommy!
母亲的双眼
译者:微博@Emtee
译者：微博@Emtee